Phil: Where I work, we have a school-wide
positive behavior support policy,
which as I said earlier you really do
see the direct correlation when that's
implemented well and a consistent
approach is important as well as.
A reward system, first of all,  we use
Class Dojo, which is used, I've seen used
in quite a lot of other schools actually.
And to reinforce that we have four/five
categories: so it's independent,
safe and sensible, being considerate
to others and then, so aiming
high, being prepared and engaged.
So, five or six, but there's a
couple sort of grouped in together.
So when we see those behaviors, we
make it clear and you know, that
positive behavior has happened.
Like, "oh, you held the door open for
me there, that was really considerate".
And then would reinforce it with
like, with a considerate dojo points.
And then the points, as I said, the
points win prizes and then they have a
dojo shop so the pupils at the end of the
week will go and spend that dojo prizes.
Zoe T: You would have to use limit setting
as part of your interaction, let's say a
school, if you're working with children.
But, I wouldn't necessarily say that
that has to be done in a behaviorist way.
Again, you can approach that from a
kind of developmental perspective.
Kerry: I have a weekly meeting with a PBS
practitioner at school where we talk over
any incidents that had happened in the
week, and we really try and break down and
get to the communication of that behavior.
So what need was being met by that
behavior and how can we support it
to happen in a more functional way?
So for instance, one young person
will pull hair quite frequently.
And when we really broke down
the communication of that
behavior, it was for attention.
So it's then about making sure
that the people who are supporting
them are giving them that
hundred percent one-to-one focus.
And then we saw a decrease in the
hair pulling behaviors because
we were meeting that need.
Phil: As I mentioned earlier, you're
not, instead of being punitive, either
taking things away, you know, telling
someone off -  you really reinforce,
recognizing and reinforcing the positive
behaviors that are desirable, not only
in school, but you know, in life which
I think is also important, linking it
all back to life outside of the school.